DRASHTEE PARMAR

Kennesaw, GA 30144 | (678) 467-4208 | drashteeparmar@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/drashteeparmar

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

An experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated background in designing and implementing software systems and applications. A keen ability to work with developers to produce intellectual property that meets design schedules and customer functional and quality requirements. Experienced with the aspect of front-end application design as well as back-end verification and validation.

EDUCATION

Master of Science Computer Science,

Currently Pursuing – May 2023

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta GA Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering,

May 2019

Kennesaw State University, Marietta GA

Associate of Science in Computer Programming,

May 2016

Chattahoochee Technical College, Marietta GA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

Tools: IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Apache Web Server, Software Development Lifecycle, Software Development

Methodologies, GitHub, Jenkins CI CD Pipelines, Database, MS Office Suites (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint,

Outlook, Visio)

Certifications: Java Programmer Certification; SWAGGA Certificate for Service Learning **Organizations:** Developers Student Club, Society of Women Engineers, WIT

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Application Developer

2019 - 2021

ADP, Alpharetta GA

- Executed object-oriented analysis & design, unit testing, and code coverage.
- Developed code in line with Agile and Test-Driven Development Methodologies.
- Worked with Kafka, AWS, ICP, RESTful API, Swagger, Splunk.
- Initialized a project for Notifications, Tasks, and Global Audit Log using Spring Boot Micro API Services.
- Oversaw technical support and troubleshooting for client-facing issues.

Global Product and Technology Development Intern

2018 - 2018

ADP, Alpharetta GA

- Led debugging for various applications at functional, design, and programming levels using Java.
- Managed Rally and JIRA Boards for keeping track of activities.
- Participated actively in Scrum ceremonies.

Quality Assurance 2012 – 2018

Philips Respironics, Kennesaw GA

- Tested oxygen and medical devices to ensure operational functionality.
- Closely monitored all stages of the process to ensure a high-quality product.
- Trained employees to successfully maintaining quality and compliance standards.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Introduction to Database, Kennesaw State University

Fall 2017

Created a custom shopping cart for a cake-selling web application using Visual Studio and MVC frame. Worked on Data Processing, Data Modeling, Database Design, Development, and Implementation.

DeRiche Agency, Inc., Chattahoochee Technical College

Fall 2015

- Designed and presented solutions to build an internal website for the disability service provider.
- Developed a web-based internal employee management system with C#.Net and MySQL.
- Designed, coded, tested, and aggregated results from SQL queries to provide information to the clients.
- Captured required information with audit logs and supported workflow using Linux Operating System.